how are we going to negotiate with you
как мы собираемся Договариваться с вами
with us with everyone How are you going to
с нами со всеми Как вы собираетесь с
negotiate with us I can’t even imagine
нами договориться я даже не представляю
because no one is going to negotiate with you anymore
потому что с вами никто уже
Europe
договариваться не собирается Европа
America is clearly with us and everyone understands that
Америка чётко с нами и все понимают что
Russia will get stars on the battlefield and
Россия получит звездюлей на поле боя и
will have nothing to do with it  you can
будет ей о чём с вами можно
negotiate
договариваться
Hello, shake your hand
Здравствуйте руку качайте
yes to the left I understand yes I can hear the pump
да ко левая я понял да слышно чтоб помпу
Yes I’m from Ukraine the city of Khmelnitsky And
Да я из Украины город Хмельницкий А вы
where are you from
откуда
Oh I’m surava and the
О я сурава а
city is the city of Yekaterinburg o Ekb the very
город город Екатеринбург о Екб самый
center of the Urals Ural Ural straight Yes you’ll
центр Урала Урал Урал прям Да вы там всю
roll out all the water there right now
воду выкате за сейчас Ну
Well no  there will be water left in the Urals I
да не останется воды на Урале Я это
wanted to ask how you feel about a
хотел спросить как вы относитесь к
special military
специальной военной
operation, how to
операции как к ней
treat it, I’m not saying how to treat it,
относиться Я же не говорю Как относиться
I’m saying how you feel about any military
Я говорю как вы относитесь любые боевые
action - This is bad, it turns out that
действия - Это плохо то получается
Russia will do the wrong thing by attacking
Россия неправильно сделает что напала на
Ukraine, but Ukraine did the right thing  what
Украину а а Украина правильно делала что
they unpacked
распаковали
ra is the wrong
ра неправильный
question and what is the right Which is the right one Well, well,
вопрос а який пра Какой правильный Ну ну
the right one And you condemn the actions
правильный А вы осуждаете действия
that took place for 8 years, I condemn you
которые происходили 8 лет у вас осуждаю
yes Russia attacked Ukraine 8 years ago and
да Россия 8 лет назад напала на Украину
captured By the way, nine have already been 9 years 9
захватила Вот кстати девять уже 9 лет 9
years The fact is that yes on the night of the 26th  above
лет Дело в том что да в ночь с 26 над
all, Russia captured Crimea And then on
сеь Россия захватила Крым Да и дальше
April 12, 2014 it attacked the
ещё 12 апреля 2014 года напала на
Donetsk Lugansk region
донецкую луганскую область
Yes there and in Odessa in Odessa you there
Да там же да в Одессе в Одессе у вас там
in Odessa Yes in Odessa, look at that already Yes The
в Одессе Да в Одессе это уже смотри Да
Russian FSB wanted to undermine Ukraine
Российская ФСБ хотела расшатать Украину
and in Odessa I wanted to proclaim it too
так и в Одессе Хотела провозгласить тоже
there they threw your people, let’s say the
там пнр бросали ваши вот эти скажем
FSS, first they attacked a peaceful
фсш сначала напали на мирную
demonstration, they shot Yes, here in
демонстрацию расстреливали Да у нас в
Odessa they then they ran away to this house
Одессе они потом они убежали в этот дом
of Trade Unions, they threw Molotov cocktails from
Профсоюзов кидали коктейли Молотова
above yes And that’s why the fire started Well,
сверху да И из-за чего начался пожар Ну
that’s it, everyone got out of the smoke-filled
и вот да все Выбрались из задымления
premises, that is  there the Armed Forces of the FSB
помещений то есть там там ВС фсбшники
are to blame yes Well,
виноваты да Ну
yes, sometimes they have fias yes then how
да бывает у них фиас да то вы как
do you think that it is right
получается считаете что правильно
to do that Russia attacked Ukraine
сделать что Россия напала на Украину
yes You have to defend your interests
да Надо же отстаивать свои интересы
What kind of
Какие все
Europe are you all striving to join NATO yes So what does it
вот Европа вы вот стремитесь в НАТО да
matter to you what
разница
NATO told you  30 years ago we
НАТО говорила ещё 30 лет назад мы не
will not expand to the east
будем расширяться на восток
they are how old are you? 30 30 yes, that is,
они Вам сколько лет мне 30 30 да то есть
when you were born NATO said that we will not
когда вы родились НАТО сказала что мы не
expand to the
расширим на
east from the Berlin STM
восток сде берлинской СТМ
I honestly don’t remember in the nineties in the
Я честно не помню в девяностом в
nineties Most likely in the nineties Yes, in
девяностом Скорее всего в девяностом Да
my opinion  eighty-nine Yes EU Well,
по-моему восемьдесят девятом Да ЕС А ну
let’s now I’m already interested, yes,
давайте сейчас Мне аж интересно да
ninety or eighty-nine,
девяносто или восемьдесят девятый
in my opinion, until ninety,
по-моему до девяностого восемьдесят
eighty-eighth or eighty-nine, I don’t
восьмой или восемьдесят девятый я не
remember Honestly, I don’t remember either Now
помню Честно говоря тоже не помню Сейчас
we’ll see and let’s see about the light, let’s see
мы посмотрим да про светимся посмотрим
the fall of the [ __ ] on November 9, eighty-nine,
падение дего 9 ноября восемьдесят
eighty-nine  Well,
девятого года восемьдесят девятого Ну
almost yes, I understood well and said NATO
почти да понял хорошо и сказала НАТО не
will not expand and that’s
будет расширяться и что ну и расширилась
where Estonia Latvia Lithuania expanded into NATO.
вот там Эстония Латвия Литва в НАТО
And
вошли И
that’s
что это же
bad. What’s bad is that people want to join NATO,
плохо Что плохо хотят люди выйти в НАТО
what difference does it make?
входят какая разница
Well, for the security of our country, for the
Ну для безопасности нашей страны для
security of whom our country and
безопасности кого нашей страны а что а
what’s wrong with your country? Are you
что там с вашей страной не так Вы что
afraid of
боитесь
NATO? Well, it’s the
НАТО Ну как надо это сейчас самый
largest military bloc now. Well, look,
крупный военный блок Ну так смотрите
if uh, that is, NATO needed to
если ээ то есть НАТО надо на вас
attack you. That’s what I can’t
нападать было Вот и что я не могу
understand; NATO is deploying for something. Well
понять НАТО же размещает для чего-то Ну
look, if you are such a new state
смотри если вы настолько ное государство
that you are Ukraine. For example, it’s
что вас Украина Вот например
not even NATO that is firing at you, but Ukraine, so
обстреливает даже не НАТО а Украина так
shelling your Belgorod region,
обстреливать вашу Белгородскую область
like Kursk-Bryansk, today
так курскую брянскую вон сегодня
they flew to St. Petersburg, flights were canceled Yes,
прилетали в в Питере отменяли полёты Да
because it flew there, uh, our St.
из-за того что долетела туда ээ наша
Petersburg did not fly there, there was just a UFO there  Yes,
Питер не долетела просто там НЛО было да
there was a UFO Yes, what was flying there, that the
там было НЛО Да а что там летало что
airport was closed, there were exercises, and
закрыли аэропорт там учения были а
Moscow and summer Yes, 100 kilometers to
Москву да лета Да 100 километров до
Moscow Kolomna Yes Far away, guess what? Yes, I’m
Москвы Коломну Да Дале те Прикинь Да я
actually reading Kolomna today. In short, he
вообще сегодня читаю Коломну Короче
almost didn’t make it, something there, he didn’t
чуть-чуть не долетел что-то там ему не
have enough gasoline  or whatever it is he
хватило этого бензина или что там чем он
eats so much in Tuaps flew
там питается во столько в туапс долетела
to Napa damn it flies from Ukraine flies at
в напу блин летает из Украины летает на
you flies and flies and you
вас летает и летает и вы ничего не
can’t do anything Why are
можете сделать А что так
you asking me this question Well, yeah, well, it’s not
ты мне задаёшь этот вопрос Ну да ну не
like that, you’re an expert, I’m I  not a military
так вы ж вы ж Эксперт я я не военный
person, not well, you’re such an expert on
человек не ну вы такой эксперт по
NATO expansion In short, if Well, I’m
расширению НАТО Короче если Ну я тебе
just telling you about the geopolitical I don’t
говорю просто про геополитический Я не
know why it’s good. But for example, specifically,
знаю почему хорошо А например конкретно
here’s what’s a plus for you as a citizen of the Russian
вот вам Как гражданину Российской
Federation from this war
Федерации от этой войны какой
Personally for me Well, yes Personally for me no
плюс Лично мне Ну да Лично мне никакого
what can I get  plus I don’t
какой мне может быть плюс мне не
get paid extra,
доплачивает
you need it, you need it specifically,
она вам нужна вот вам конкретно э
war, no one needs war at all. Well, you
война война вообще никому не нужна Ну вы
say that it’s right that Russia attacked
говорите что правильно Россия напала на
Ukraine, why exactly do you need this
Украину вам для чего это конкретно вам
in your
на вашей
kitchen, I’m telling you again,
кухне я вам ещё раз
you want to join NATO
говорю вы хотите войти в НАТО
Yes, that’s how NATO places it on  border with Russia,
Да так НАТО размещает на грани с Россией
the base is permissible, it is
базу допустим
not permissible, it is 100%, yes, it’s good, well,
не допустим это 100% да хорошо ещё Ну
here you are, how long is
вам вот вы сколько сколько сколько под
the flight to Moscow, how long is the flight to Moscow,
лёт до Москвы сколько под лёт до Москвы
how many, how many minutes I don’t know, look
сколько ну сколько минут Не знаю смотри
from Ukraine because how far away they opened the
от Украины так как далеко открывали
map Estonia Latvia Lithuania is closer to
карту Эстония Латвия Литва ближе к
Moscow than  Ukraine is true if you are now
Москве чем Украина правда если вы сейчас
You if you are now sending drones
Вы если вы сейчас беспилотники посылаете
as you say all the way to St. Petersburg then that’s
как вы говорите до самого Питера то
correct Yes, with the same success
правильно Да таким же с таким же успехом
you can from the border
вы с границы
How many from to
можете Сколько от до на
kilometers does the Leningrad region have a
километров у Ленинградской области есть
border with
граница с
NATO and that is, the Leningrad region is
НАТО и то есть Ленинградская область она
already in  connected to NATO What does Ukraine have to do with it
уже в притык к НАТО Причём тут Украина
from Ukraine to the Leningrad region and even
от Украины до Ленинградской области да и
to the Moscow region further than from
до Московской области дальше чем от
Latvia Lithuania Estonia And now there will also be
Латвии Литвы Эстонии А теперь ещё будет
Finland there and Sweden
Финляндия там и Швеция
Oh well, let's let someone else go Let's
Да ладно давай допустим другого пойдём
start in
Давай начали в четырнадцатом
14, let's let these pro-Russian comrades
году допустим пророссийские эти товарищи
be indignant yes
возмущаться да
So this is for you  I didn’t like it
Так вам это не понравилось
and you started
и и вы начали их
pinching them everywhere, for example, like this Prim Well, the
везде прищемить например как это Прим Ну
Russian language can’t be covered now. I
русский язык сейчас нельзя накра В
mean, you can’t, and I, what
смысле нельзя а я я на каком с вами
language are you talking to? Well, officially, you can’t do
разговори языке Ну официально же нельзя
that officially, we’ve never had it from
так официально никогда не было у нас с
what point in the Kharkov region  the
какого пере у вас в Харьковской области
governor there or whoever he is in your
губернатор там или кто он у вас там
city, he He still
городской он Он и сейчас по-русски
speaks Russian And
разговаривает И
[applause]
[аплодисменты]
that Well, yes, because he has to And
что Ну да да потому что должен А у вас
look at you, what language should they
смотрите у вас на каком языке должны
speak? How many nationalities
разговаривать Сколько национальностей
live in the Russian
живёт в Российской
Federation in peace? Everything is in the national
Федерации спокойно Все на национально
language  let's talk like this, the governor of
языке разговарить давайте так губернатор
yours is Ekaterinburg, what language does he
вашего это Екатеринбурга на каком языке
speak in Russian in Russian And what is not
говорит на русском на русском А что не
in Chuvash because it is not Chuvash Yeah,
на чувашском потому что не Чуваши Ага
well the Chuvash parliament can and
хорошо чувашском парламенте может и по
don’t look in Chuvash Let’s
чувашски не смотри Давайте можете мне
show me, for example,
показать например
open at least one website
открыть хоть один сайт
There are governments of the Republic of Tatarstan
Там правительства республики Татарстана
or Bashkartastan so  it was not in
или башкартастан чтобы он был не на
Russian but in Tatar or there
русском а на татарском или там на
should be a dual language there, but where is it?
двойном языке должно быть а где вот
Show me, find it, I was looking for something, we do
Покажите найдите я искал что-то
n’t have it, we have a Tatar TV channel, a Tatar TV channel,
нету у нас есть татарский
and that
телеканал татарский телеканал и что
TV channels, whatever TV channels you want, you can
телеканал телеканалы какие хочешь можешь
make. We also have a Tatar TV channel.
сделать У нас тоже татарский телеканал
And what is there?  Chuvash TV channel Well, so
есть И что есть чувашский телеканал Ну и
what? And yes, all state
что да А да а все государственные
documents are in Russian, why so, well,
документы идут на русском почему так ну
because it’s state-owned, so And
потому что он государственный так вот А
we have a Ukrainian state-owned problem in the World Cup. Well, you’re
у нас украинский государственны в ЧМ
banning Nar I
проблема Ну вы же запрещать нару
’m talking to you in Russian, who’s
говорю с вами на русском языке кто мне
banning me? Well, go to  street,
запрещает Ну вы Выйдите на улицу
speak
поговорите на
Russian you speak on the street Well, I do
русском вы разговариваете на улице Ну я
n’t know, I’m located 3,000 km from you,
не знаю я я ж нахожусь 3.000 км от вас
I’m interested I’m interested, what do you
мне интересно Мне интересно а что вы
know about Ukraine if in Ukraine you
знаете про Украину если в Украине
speak on the
заговорить на
street, I’m quieter because suddenly the neighbors
улице я тише потому что вдруг соседи
somewhere will hear If in Russian  finds out that
где-то услышат Если по-русски узнает что
I speak Russian, what will happen to me I
я говорю по-русски что будет мне
know This is your law Well, what do you think,
знаю Это ваши закон Ну как вы думаете
according to our laws, if the neighbors
что по нашим законам если вот соседи
hear, they can call the SBU Hello, I have a
услышат они могут позвонить в СБУ Алло У
neighbor here who speaks Russian Well,
меня тут сосед по-русски разговаривает
what will happen, well, I’m asking you,
Ну что будет ну я я вас спрашиваю может
maybe  something like that Well, maybe probably what what
быть что-то такое Ну может наверное а
what according to our laws will it be for
что что что по нашим законам будет за
speaking in
разговор на русском
Russian I don’t know I don’t know your laws
языке я не знаю я не знаю ваши законы
So what are you telling us What’s
Так а что вы нам какой-то Говорите Что у
forbidden there forbidden to
нас там запретили запретили
talk if you don’t know
разговаривать если вы не знаете
Well who  spoke So he says, well, he wants in
Ну кто говорил Так и говорит ну хочет на
Ukrainian, he wants in Russian Yes, but a
украинском хочет на русском Да но
state deputy must
государственно депутат должен
speak in Ukrainian, the
разговаривать на украинском языке
president must speak in
президент должен разговаривать на
Ukrainian, official
украинском языке официальный
document flow is in Ukrainian,
документооборот на украинском языке в
what is
чём
your problem in general, what is your current
проблема ваша вообще какая сейчас
position, well,
позиция вот ну
political, clarify what you
политическая уточните что вы имеете в
mean, well,
виду ну
plan How are you going to How are we going to
плане Как вы собира Как мы собираемся
negotiate with you with us with everyone
Договариваться с вами с нами со всеми
How are you going to come to an agreement with us I
Как вы собираетесь с нами договориться я
can’t even imagine because no
даже не представляю потому что с вами
one is going to negotiate with you anymore
никто уже договариваться не собирается
Europe America is clearly with us and everyone
Европа Америка чётко с нами и все
understands that Russia will receive lei on the
понимают что Россия получит лей на поле
battlefield and will  What can we negotiate with you?
боя и будет е о чём с вами можно
Let's hypothetically
договариваться Давай гипотетически
say what will happen next, let's
ги дальше что будет а давайте из чего
look at what this hypothetically will be like if
такая гипотетико будет смотрите если
you get it all year round, I just
целый год в год вы получаете я я просто
suggested it, I'm not saying that this will happen.
предложил не утверждаю что так буде
escaped from Chernigovskaya Sumy escaped
с Черниговской убежала Сумской убежала
Nikolaevskaya escaped Zhitomirskaya
Николаевской убежала Житомирской убежала
escaped Kharkovskaya escaped from Kherson they knocked
Харьковской убежала с Херсона выбили так
you out of the estuary in Donetsk you were knocked out of the estuary in the
в Донецке из лимана вас выбили в
Donetsk region, that is, for the
Донецкой области да то есть вас
last 9 months you have only been knocked out,
последние 9 месяцев только выбивают
knocked out, and they are giving us more and
выбивают выбивают а нам всё больше и
more foreign weapons, and then
больше иностранного оружия дают да то
hypothetically Russia will lose.
гипотетически Россия проиграет Вот
let's do this hypothetical scenario,
давайте Такой гипотетический сценарий
look, Ukraine is knocking
делать смотрите Украина так выбивает
Russia out of the Donetsk region of the Lugansk
Россию из Донецкой области Луганской
region and Crimea and how it will further
области и Крыма так дальше как будет
develop, how will you negotiate with us?
развиваться как вы будете с нами
Well, in your opinion, how will we
договариваться Ну по-вашему как мы будем
negotiate? Well, look, we
договариваться Ну вот смотрите мы
have destroyed where you need to go to
разгромили откуда вам надо идти чтобы с
start negotiating with us  no,
нами начать договариваться нет вот
look, we, we defeated you in the Crimea, in the
смотрите мы вот мы вас разбили в Крыму в
Donetsk region, in the Lugansk region, we reached
Донецкой области в Луганской вышли на
our borders in 1991, and
свои границы э девяносто первого года да
before that we knocked you out in Transnistria along with
до этого выбили в Приднестровье вместе с
the Moldovans and the Romanians, uh
молдована и румына вас ээ
So you, all of you, ran away behind
Так что вы вот вы такие все убежали за
the curb Yes, Putin is shaking  he thinks Damn,
поребрик Да Путин трясётся э думает Блин
they can take the Belgorod region now,
они сейчас ещё Белгородскую область
since you will negotiate with us
так как вы будете с нами договариваться
so that we do not touch Belgorod Krasnodar
чтобы мы не трогали Белгород Краснодар
Rostov And you will touch Belgorod, and
Ростов А вы будете трогать Белгород а
why not Why not and where will you
чём бы и не Почему бы и нет и докуда Вы
go? Well, for example, Belgorod is
пойдёте А ну например до Белгорода
generally 20 km from  We arrived in the Kharkov region
вообще 20 км от Харьковской области
and we’ll take everything like reparations,
доехали и всё как репарации заберём все
for example,
например
then no. Well, look no. Well, then
дальше не Ну вот смотрите Не Ну дальше
we got to Belgorod
что до Белгорода дошли дальше Вот
next. They took Belgorod first. Yes,
Белгород сначала Белгород забрали Да
for example, or
например или
they took it there, for example, in the Rostov region,
там взяли например в Ростовской области
like reparations took away your factories there, and
как репарации забрали там ваши заводы и
so on, all those factories like
так дальше все те заводы типа это такое
Yes, yes, you’re right, there’s nothing there. I
да Да вы правы там нема что Забирать
agree,
согласен
here we are coming. Yes, here’s Belgorod. That’s
вот мы приходим Да вот Белгород
right. Because it’s so hard to re-educate so many of them
Правильно Потому что это ж столько этих
later with
перевоспитывать потом мозгами
such brains. Why do we need only
такими этоже тяжело будет Зачем нам лько
cotton voters? Yes, I agree. In short, we
Избирателей ватных Да согласен Короче мы
reached the Borders of the ninety-first year
вышли на Границы девяносто первого года
and we just continue  missile
так и продолжаем просто ракетными
systems to overwhelm your Belgorod
системами заваливать ваш этот Белгород
Krasnodar Rostov airplanes fly to
Краснодар Ростов самолётики летают на
St. Petersburg to Moscow to Yekaterinburg
Питер на Москву на Екатеринбург
you are shouting something there Well, let's
вы там что-то кричите Ну давайте
negotiate Let's negotiate
договариваться Давайте договариваться мы
about the World Cup Let's get your
такие о ЧМ Давайте ваше
proposal, I don't see it even
предложение я не вижу такое даже
hypothetical, well,
гипотетическое ну как гипотетико
look hypothetically from Kharkov in the Kiev
смотрите с Харьковской в Киевской
region We  you were knocked out, reached your
области Мы вас выбили вышли на свою
border Yes, they did it in Zhitomir, yes, in
границу Да в Житомирской сделали да в
Chernigov Sumskaya, also in Kharkov
Черниговской Сумской тоже в Харьковской
vyzhi bang, finally we heard
выжи бах наконец-то у нас прозвучало
the word Bach everyone I have the word
слово Бах каждый У меня есть слово
bakhmut Everything when there is nothing to say Everyone says
бахмут Все когда нечего ска Все говорят
bakhmut bakhmut I’ve been saying bakhmut for six months already,
бахмут бахмут мне уже полгода говорят
well, tell me what  in our
бахмут а ну расскажите что у нас в
Bakhmut I don’t know, you know better, you know better
бахмуте Я не знаю вам виднее вам поближе
Bakhmut Well, so what did you say
бахмут Ну да так что что ба вы сказали
Bakhmut and I’m asking you what you have
бахмут и я вас спрашиваю что у вас
Bakhmut And what do you have in Vladivostok Well in
бахмуте А что у вас во Владивостоке Ну в
Bakhmut how Bakhmut stood and it still stands and
бахмуте как стоял бахмут так и стоит и
everything is fine Well  Yes, there are so many of
что стоит нормально всё Ну да столько
your Russians There, they just saw
ваших русских Там просто жесть видели
Prigozhin showing the lack of shells,
Пригожин показывал снарядов не хвата
a photo of the SGO ko guns, because of this they saw
фотку сго ко боов изза этого видели
what is your proposal We went
что де ваше предложение Мы вышли
to the borders of the ninety-first year,
на границ девяносто первого года свои
took our lands and
забрали земли и
shelled the base, we say everything
обстреливала ет базу мы говорим всё
Let's come here Let's come here all
Давайте на сюда Давайте сюда всякие
sorts of things  ki
такие ки
What will you negotiate about? We won’t
О чём будете договариваться мы не будем
negotiate, but what will you endure
договариваться а что вы будете терпеть
our
наши
shelling? You won’t even get to the
обстрелы вы не дойдёте даже до
Belgorod region, in the sense that we are already
Белгородской области в смысле так мы уже
on the border of the Belgorod region, there
на границе Белгородской области
will be a complete
произойдёт полная
mobilization of the couple and they will be called in.
мобилизация четы призовут и на Хорошо
Okay, let’s get all of you mobilized.
Давайте Так вот вас всех мобили Зро всех
all all all yes at the World Cup you
всех всех всех всех всех да на ЧМ вы
will fight with
будете воевать
nothing I ask Just what with
чем нечем спрашиваю Просто чем там
sticks stones
палками камнями
pistols laze now 300 now 300
пистолетами лазе сейчас 300 сейчас 300
are mobilizing something well now 300 what
мобилизуют что-что ну сейчас 300 чем вот
look here for example you mobilized 10 million
смотрите вот например вы мобили 10 млн
people what they will fight with they
людей чем чем они будут воевать это они
will Booth 10  Immediately mobiles Zro skaz
будут Бут 10 сразу мобили Зро сказа
good You said all the mobiles but not
хорошо Вы сказали всех мобилие да не
right away what they will
сразу же чем они будут
fight with I’m telling you not right away Well
воевать я тебе говорю не сразу же Ну
good Immediately look mobiles are coming 300
хорошо Сразу смотри идёт мобили 300
people they are moving forward the country is huge with
человек они идут вперёд страна огром с
flags how much seis now you have
флагами скоко сейс сейчас у тебя
how much is the army of Ukraine how much no idea
сколько армия Украины скоко понятия неме
Well  approximately I don’t know at all I know completely I
Ну примерно вообще не знаю на зна полна
don’t
не
know I don’t have this information Well
знаю не владею этой информацией Ну
approximately I don’t know at all I think they
примерно вообще не знаю Я думаю нам
don’t tell us exactly the numbers that you didn’t
точно не говорят цифр что вы не
know Well, let’s just wipe it off with something, here the
знали Ну давай нето чем вытри вот нам
American gives us
Американ дают
the height of the hars, he’s a bunch of yours 500 were in
высото харс он ваших куча 500 было в
this at the vocational school hars  covers vocational schools 500 no
этом в ПТУ харс накрывает ПТУ 500 нету
Saratov and Samara Hello Yes, but when they
Саратов и Самара Привет Да а вот при
took another 500, what will they do with them Well,
взяли ещё 500 что с ними делать будут Ну
how is this not a war, you know,
вот как это ж не война знаете какая-то
somewhere ancient people with a club there ran with
где-то древние люди с дубина там бежали
stones, fought there with a club That's what What will you
камнями бились там дубина Вот что Что вы
do  I’m also throwing missiles at you.
делать также ракетами те вас закидываю
Wait, why, if you don’t have missiles,
Подождите то зачем если у вас е ракеты
then why do you need to throw
да то зачем вам миллион людей закидывай
missiles at a million people, why don’t you throw them? And who
ракетами что ж вы не закидывай А кто
will clear the territory, and that is, you
будет территорию то зачищать а то есть
need to throw missiles at them and then they’ll send
надо закидать ракетами а потом пойдут
a clearer? Yes, why don’t
зачиститель да А почему сейчас не
you throw these
кидаете эти
missiles now?  So that’s the way it should be. It’s cool, I
ракеты Значит так надо Прикольно да
love these kitchen philosophers, you know,
люблю вот этих кухонных философов знаете
they’re all such warriors, just awesomely
они вот все такие вояки просто офигенно
cool, and what do you work for? By the way, I’m a
круто да А вы кем работаете Кстати я
mechanic, a mechanic, how much is your salary?
слесарь слесарь да сколько зарплата у
100 in what
вас 100 в какой
currency, in rubles, how much is it in dollars?
валюте в рублях это в долларах
Calculate I don’t know what the exchange rate is,
сколько Посчитай Я не знаю какой курс
how much  you have a dollar, where do I know? I don’t
сколько у вас доллар откуда зна Я не
count the exchange rate. I don’t keep my currency in dollars,
считаю за курсом Я в долларах не держу
only in rubles. Of course, it’s a
валюту только в рублях держите конечно
very correct strategy, especially
очень правильная стратегия особенно
now, well, America will collapse, you know, these
сейчас ну Америка рухнет знаешь эти
dollars are pieces of paper that are not
доллары это бумажки ничем не
backed by anything, so throw them away later, and the ruble,
обеспеченные так их выкинуть потом а руб
he never failed, he
он никогда не подвед
understood, and the machine  What kind of Honda do you have?
понял а машина у вас какая у меня Honda
And what’s not
А что не
Russian? I haven’t earned money yet on Russian. Russian is more expensive,
русская не заработал ещё на русс русская
of course, it’s amazing. I realized that the
дороже конечно [__] Я понял что
Japanese don’t drive Russian cars
японцы не ездят на русских машинах
because they’re
потому что это
expensive, our
дорого у нас
quality is yes. And what’s the highest
качество да А какая у вас самая
quality car you have? Here’s one that’s
качественная машина Вот такая чтоб
more expensive than a Honda
дороже хонд
Ultrasound UAZ  Yes, of course, wait, I can’t help but
УЗИ УАЗик Да конечно подождите я не могу
laugh, the dude sold it, I sold a kidney, I bought
заржать чувак продал Продал почку купил
a UAZ. Although maybe yours are really
УАЗик Хотя может у вас и действительно
more expensive, they’re just,
дороже они просто
uh, well, it’s not better, but more expensive, that is,
ээ ну оно же не лучше а дороже то есть
it’s worse. But I don’t have a new
оно хуже У меня же у меня же не новая
Conda, what are you? Well, let’s compare
конда что ты А ну давайте сравнивать
the same And what you couldn’t buy is not a
одинаково А что вы не могли купить не
new UAZ
новый УАЗик
If there is a new Honda and a new UAZ, which is
Если есть новая Honda и новый УАЗик что
cheaper Oh, not a new Honda and not a new
дешевле Ой да не новая Honda и не новый
UAZ, which is cheaper Yes, which will be cheaper, well,
УАЗик что дешевле Да что будет дешевле
probably the UAZ will be cheaper But why did
ну наверное УАЗик будет подешевле А что
you buy a non-Russian one
же вы купили нду не русскую
because it  more expensive, well, look,
потому что она подороже ну вот смотри
with two RAUs, firstly, come on, let's
при двох РАУ во-первых давай давай давай
think logically, the best
размышлять логически самый лучший
auto industry in general in the world is Japanese.
автопром вообще в мире это японский
Cool, yes, why not the
Прикольно да А почему не
Russian ones, ours
русский наши
just can’t do it? Well, what
только не умеют делать Ну а а что Россия
can Russia do? By the way, it’s
умеет делать кстати вот
interesting that they can make tanks only
интересно умеет танки делать только
tanks A  what kind of good tanks do you make,
танки А какие вы танки хорошие делаете
where are they there for a special operation? Well, the T-90, I
где они там на спецоперации Ну т-90 я
know that there is a T-90 there - what year is this a
знаю что там есть т-90 - это какого года
tank from the twelfth year? Soviet these are
танк двенадцатого ещё Советский это
Soviet tanks from the
советские танки ещё
T90 of the ninety-twelfth year
Т90 девяносто двенадцатого года
Look at this now, I’ll look at it, they
Смотри это сейчас я посмотрю это
loaded it with something and  so T90 back in the
напикали его чем-то а так Т90 ещё При
Soviet Union there was
Союзе был
T90, here's T90 - yes,
Т90 вот Т90 - это да
T90m is a deep modernization of a
т90м это глубокая модернизация сного
battle tank from the ninety-second year of
боевого танка девяносто второго года
production, what is it now?
выпуска что сейчас сечас Сейчас подожди
- this is what
Т90 Т90 - это что у
we have Or maybe not now Maybe I’m not an expert
нас А може не сечас Может быть я не спец
just in Tanks
просто в Танках
sori koche T90 modernization of the
сори коче Т90 модернизация
T-72 to the T90 damn it in the eighty-ninth
т-72 во Т90 блин в восемьдесят девятом
year in Nizhny Tagil, in short, you’re
году в Нижнем Тагиле се же короче вы
just modernizing This is fundamentally
просто модернизирует Это принципиально
not a new tank, you’re just modernizing a
не новый танк вы просто модернизирует
Soviet tank  and that’s it Well, it’s not Soviet
советский танк и всё Ну он не Советский
Well, it was released by you and like, well,
Ну выпущенный у вас да типа ну
developments Well, according to the scheme for
разработки Ну по схема по системах
active protection systems and so on
активной защиты и так дальше
Well Well, the Soviet tank is still outdated Yes, and Abrams is
Ну Ну Советский ещё устаревший танк Да а
not outdated
Абрамс не устаревший
Tank M To be honest, I don’t know, I don’t know, but
Танк М честно говоря не знаю не знаю но
it seems to me that Abrams is outdated with  an
мне кажется что устаревший Абрамс с
outdated T90 is like an outdated UAZ
устаревшим Т90 это как устаревший УАЗик
and an outdated Honda, you really think both are
и устаревшая Honda правда думаешь и то и
outdated, but there is a nuance True Well, I
то устаревшая но есть нюанс Правда Ну я
don’t think so, yes, it’s good if you watch And
так не думаю да Хорошо если смотрите А
if you make such cool tanks
если вы такие классные танки делаете
Why are you losing in Ukraine
Почему же вы проигрываете в Украине
Well, you also had an Armata tank like that
Ну у вас ещё танк армата был такой
remember they
помните
said now there is Yes, but for some reason they
говорили сейчас есть Да но он что-то вот
took him around Red Square at the parade, he
по Красной площади на параде возили он
got stuck there birr-birr-birr in the hole, they
там застрял быр-быр-быр по дырка больше
don’t take him anywhere else in the war They don’t
его нигде не вывозят на войне Не
use Yes, for some reason, well, he wasn’t there
используют Да почему-то ну не он там
somewhere skating, skating in short  I rode
где-то катался катался короче катался
there but not to the point I rode to Ukraine I understood
там но не до катался до Украины Я понял
well what else are you saying that Russia
хорошо что же вы ещ что Россия
produces something so that the whole world can buy
производит такого чтобы весь мир покупал
something of high quality in
что вот качественного в
Russia if it is such a great power and
России если это великая держава такая а
Ukraine is a Great Power So wait, we
Украина Великая держава Так подождите Мы
don’t attack others, in short, there is something to
же не нападаем на других короче там что
capture us  they want NATO And so
нас захватить хотят НАТО И так
on Let’s put NATO in a different way, see that it’s
дальше Давай по-другому НАТО смотри что
not Russia Russia for 30 years Who was
не Россия Россия за 30 лет На кого
attacked
напала
Moldova Ukraine Georgia
на Молдову на Украину на Грузию
is that just like that it’s
это то что вот так
going to Chechnya or more precisely like
сходу на Чечню на точнее так на
Ichkeria Ichkeria is internal what
ичкери Ичкерия - это внутренняя какой
internally it declared
внутренне она провозгласила
independence yet  before the collapse of the Soviet
независимость ещё до распада Советского
Union, the DPR also declared
Союза вас у вас ДНР тоже провозгласила
independence. Wait No, look at the DPR -
независи Подождите Нет смотрите ДНР -
It was your troops that entered Yes and they stationed
Это ваши войска вошли Да и поставили там
some there And in this viri Yes, it
каких-то А в этом вири Да официально
was official and the
было и выборы
presidential elections of this Dudayev were elected
президента этого Дудаев же был избран
Okay, come on, what's next, so
Ладно давай давай че дальше так вот
tell me  We're talking about Russia, what is Russia,
скажите Мы ж про Россию что вот Россия
if Russia is such a country that
если Россия Такая страна что её хотят
everyone wants to take it over? Yes, for example, what does
все захватить Да например что такое у
Russia have? That's why America NATO should
России Вот почему Америка НАТО должна
take over Russia
захватить Россию
you are oil, that oil is an energy resource. So you already
вы нефть что нефть энергоресурс Так вы и
sell your energy resources, like,
так свои энергоресурсы продаёте типа и
well, so it will be cheaper for someone  that
что ну Так дешевле будет дешевле кому то
is,
есть
look. The fact is that, for example, you will
смотри Дело в том что например вам
have to pay everyone’s
придётся платить пенсии всем
American pensions and so on, why is this? Well, for
американские и так дальше зачем это Ну
example, India was once a part of the
например Индия когда-то была да частью
British Empire. Yes, why should
Великобритании империи Да зачем сейчас
Britain look now? Well, look, the point is, come on,
Британии смотри Ну смотри смысл давай
here’s yours. Well, let’s say, if you were
вот твой Хорошо давай так если бы вас
captured by America, you  would it be better to live
захватила Америка вам лучше бы жить
or would it be
стало или
worse for me? Why, for example, if
хуже по мне хуже А чем Вот например если
you became Russia became the fifty-
вы стали Россия стала там пятьдесят
first state of
первым штатом
America
Америки
so the worse it became ri and why here
так Чем хуже сталом ри да почему вот у
in Yekaterinburg specifically for you The
вас в Екатеринбурге конкретно для вас
worse life would become
Чем хуже жизнь стала
I’m telling you I don’t like America
бы я тебе говорю Мне не нравится амери А
What I don’t like I just don’t like
чем не нравится Просто не нравится
America BC and what I don’t like about it Well, I
Америка ВС а чем она не нравится Ну как
just don’t
о просто не
like the mentality And what a
нравится менталитет А какой
mentality of Freedom
менталитет Свободы
And now I understand that the Americans have a
А теперь я понял у американцев очень
lot of too much Freedom What the hell with their
много слишком Свободы Вот блин со своим
mentality Yes, they want to give freedom to
менталитетом Да свободу хотят тут дать
people in Russia, yes this  of course, if
людям в России да это же конечно если у
you have too much Freedom in Yekaterinburg,
вас в Екатеринбурге слишком много
what will it
Свободы будет Это что ж такое что ж это
be? Well, in America, you
будет Ну ты же по Америке ты по Америке
can walk around America with a gun.
можешь ходить с ружьём
Aha, by the way, it’s possible in different states
Ага ро можно мо кстати в разных штах
in different ways, yes, that is, it turns out in the
по-разному да то есть получается в
states, you can there  walk with a gun Yes,
штах можно там с пистолетом ходить Да
good And you can’t walk without
хорошо А у вас что нельзя ходить без
permission, everything is super Yes Yes And What would happen
разрешения всё супер Да Да А Что было бы
if you could walk, for example, with a
если у вас можно было ходить например с
pistol, it would be a fiasco And why is there
пистолетом было бы фиаско А почему в
no fiasco in America And what
Америке нету фиаско А что
No and what is there, well, who is Yani all the time
Нет а что там такое ну постоянно кто Яни
Yes That they were shooting so you have something to
Да Что они стреля так у вас что-нибудь
look at you had in Izhevsk Yes, there was a
смотрите у вас в Ижевской было Да вот
shooting at a school recently
недавно расстрел в школе
yes Well, that was proven by the
да Ну и что это доказала вги
American Civil Aviation Agency Every year you Look,
американска Каждый год у вас Смотри у
you can’t carry weapons, but for some reason they
вас оружие нельзя носить но почему-то
still shoot in schools Yes  why
всё равно стреляют в школах Да почему
maybe the problem is not in carrying a weapon? And in
может проблема не в ношении оружия А в
what and in something else in America
чём а в чём-то другом в Америке стреляет
Dasha shoots at a school, this is the first time and secondly in
в школу Даше это раз а во-вторых в
America this is decided by each state, for example
Америке это решает каждый штат например
in some States you can have weapons
в одних Штатах можно оружие
VH Dawa about weapons shoots at a school who
ВХ Дава про оружие стреляет в школу кто
shoots Fact  there is Who shot, here is a
стреляет Факт есть Кто стрелял вот
specific fact: who is shooting in
конкретно какой факт кто стреляет в
America? What kind of weapons did these children come from?
Америки Из какого оружия эти дети пришли
That is, the child still does not have the right to
То есть у ребёнка так ещё нету права
carry a weapon. Yes, he took his father’s
ношения оружия Да он взял отцовское
weapon and came like you, for example.
оружие и пришёл так как у Вас например
He can take his father’s hunting rifle,
Может взять отцовское ружьё охотничье
come and shoot people like he did.  you
прийти и пострелять людей как у вас
Izhevsky, yes, he didn’t shoot with a
Ижевский же было да то он же не с
legal weapon, in my opinion,
легального по-моему
what’s the problem? He who wants to
стрелял в чём проблема тот Кто хохочет
shoot people illegally goes. Yes, so
нелегально пострелять людей идёт Да так
what do you need America for example, have you become the
вот Чем вам Америка например стал ли вы
fifty-first state of America Yes, you
пятьдесят первым штатом Америки Да вы
can decide for yourself whether you can or cannot
можете сами себе решать можно или нельзя
carry weapons yes But here's the
у вас носить оружие да А вот в чём вот в
thing It's bad that there will be a lot of
чём Плохо что будет много
Freedom everyone will do what they want
Свободы все будут делать то что хотят
and a fly if in Russia everyone starts doing
а муха если в России все начнут делать
what they want I will become free And how to
что хотят свободными стану А как надо
do it And how now in Russia you
сделать А как сейчас в России вы не
can’t do what you want you do
можете делать что хотите вы делаете то
what we have is the president. As I
что наме президент Я так
understand it, you have Freedom of speech. What is it that you do
понял у тебя Свобода слова В чём
n’t have in Russia? So if
заключается не у вас в России так если
people do what they want, it will be
люди будут делать что хотят это будет
bad, yes. And now they then do
плохо да А сейчас они тогда делают что
whatever they want.
как хочет
Freedom of speech, in your opinion, is about
кто Свобода слова по-твоему это что
expressing your thoughts Yes  everywhere Well, yes, and what And
выражать свои мысли Да везде Ну да а что
where you can’t And for you Well, this makes you feel
А где нельзя А тебе Ну тебе от этого
good Well, that is, you went out there to What’s
хорошо Ну да то есть ты вышел там на Как
your name for Maidan Square in Kiev
у вас там Майдан площадь в Киеве
and criticize the authorities and
называется и покритиковать власть так и
that’s bad for you, nothing will happen to you for that Well,
это плохо тебе за это ничего не будет Ну
what’s bad is that  this makes me feel good Yes, I feel
и что плохо это от этого хорошо Да мне
good, for example, here, for example, people are
хорошо например вот у нас например люди
shouting that Zelensky is bad,
кто-то кричит что Зеленский плохой
someone is shouting that Poroshenko is bad and that
кто-то кричит что Порошенко плохой и что
this is bad, no, this doesn’t make you feel
что это плохо нет тебе от этого Хорошо
good, good, for example, if I want, look,
хорошо Вот например если я хочу Смотри
it’s my right, I can speak, I can  don’t
это моё право я могу говорить могу не
speak like that, express your thoughts,
говорить так выражать свои мысли вот
if I think that it’s good for me that I
если я считаю что мне хорошо того что я
came out and said that pensions need to be raised there, there’s a
вышел и сказал Надо пенсии там поднять
bad president who doesn’t raise
плохой такой президент что не поднимает
pensions blah blah blah yes What What’s wrong with the
пенсии бла-бла-бла да Что Что плохого в
fact that I have such a
том что у меня есть такое
right? What do you care?  -it gives Well, this Look,
право Тебе оно что-то даёт Ну это Смотри
you don’t understand what the right is to
ты не понимаешь что такое пра к тебе к
you, the power has something to do with you at all
тебе власть какое-то вообще отношение
Yes, or does the power have anything to do with me
имеет Да смот или имеет ко мне отношение
at all? I didn’t elect
власть вобще Я е избира
Yes, it does something to you, it does
Да оно к тебе что-то делает она мне
something to me, you see  you understand that
что-то вово видишь ты понимаешь что
citizens elect power and this government
граждане избирают власть и эта власть
does something for citizens in the interests of
что-то делает для граждан в интересах
citizens, at least it should do the
граждан по крайней мере должна делать
truth for me, so if I go out to
правда для меня вот я если выйду на
Red Square, it won’t make me feel
Красную Площадь мне от этого будет не
cold or hot. Well, okay, but for
холодно не жарко Ну хорошо а вот
example, if I express
например если я буду выражать свою
let’s say my position on Red Square, it won’t make me
позицию допустим на Красной площади мне
feel cold or hot, but
от этого будет ни холодно Ни жарко а
when I come to work and express
когда я приду на работу и буду выражать
my thoughts there and it will bring me
там свою мысль и она мне будет приносить
income, good for SBO, come on, so what will be
доход хорошо СБО с давай так что будет
bad if in Yekaterinburg you can
плохого если у вас в Екатеринбурге можно
express it on the square  your thoughts that it
будет выражать на площади свои мысли что
will become
Станется
bad, it will not become bad, I don’t
плохого че не станет плохого я виу не
see the point in this if people see
вижу в этом смыс если люди видят
you don’t see and people see what the
вы не видите а люди видят то в чём
problem is so that people express their thoughts
проблема чтобы люди выражали свои мысли
Going out to express what the problem is Well, so
Выходя на выражают в чём проблема Ну так
you say that like, well, this is
вы говорите что типа ну это
bad for
плохо для
for me it makes no sense for
меня для меня нет никакого смысла для
me well for you it makes no sense Yes, but
меня ну для вас нету смысла Да но а
why in Russia you can’t express this
почему в России нельзя Вот это выражать
if people want you have this former
если люди хотят вот у вас этот бывший
mayor Roizman Well, well, for the fact that he was there on
мэр Ройзман Да ну ну за то что он там в
Twitter, he just wrote short messages,
Твиттере просто писал короткие сообщения
he’s there  they started to judge, yes
его ж там судить начали да
I don’t know what he wrote there, that is, And
Я не знаю что он там писал то есть А за
why he is being pressed,
что его прессуют
I don’t know I’m
я не знаю Мне
not interested Why why Why why
неинтересно Для чего зачем Для чего
why and why do people need Freedom in general,
зачем зачем а зачем людям Свобода вообще
now I’m a free person and what is
вот я сейчас свободный человек а в чём
your Freedom I wanted to go
ваша Свобода состоит я Захотел пошёл
wherever I want
куда захочу
Anywhere, anywhere Well, for example,
Куда хоть куда Ну куда например
you went out onto the street. That’s good, an American too, then you have the same Freedom as in America, so what are you saying that in America there is a lot of Freedom in America, that person wanted to go out into the street and you went out into the street So
вышел на улицу и вы вышли на улицу Так
you  the same free How do Americans
вы такие же свободные Как американцы
get Americans if they start
получаете американцы если начнут
criticizing the authorities there, they’ll quickly start
критиковать власть там быстренько всё
howling
прихлоп воют
And I got it, I got it
А понял понял
Yeah, it’s tricky, there’s no further argument And the
Ага хитро всё нет дальше аргумента И
last thing And what does it say on your T-shirt
последнее А что у вас на футболке
that the company is a company yes And this company is
написано что фирма фирма да А эта фирма
also not Russian I understand, yes I’m not  I know
тоже не русская Я так понял да я не знаю
what and what you couldn’t
какая а а что вы не могли от Русской
buy a T-shirt from a Russian company that they don’t
фирмы футболку купить что не
make it as a gift I wear in the World Cup the
выпускают нем подарили Я ношу в ЧМ
problem is that I’m a free person and I
проблема яже свободный человек да
want to wear freedoms
свобод хочу носить
American I want to drive a Japanese car
Американо хочу ездить на японской машине
I drive free Yes I want not to go to
езжу я свободный Да хочу не выходить на
Red Square and I don’t go out Yes  I’m not going out
Красную площадь и не выхожу Да не выхожу
yes Okay,
да Хорошо
let’s be free, this is a burden, subscribe to
давай свободна это тяжесть подпишись на
th Telegram right now, he’s a
й Telegram прям зараз он а
pok tse more and more respectfully YouTube, taking
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through skarg or to your ban and even
нас через скарг ор в твый бан и дуже
more videos, I don’t show people at all times, I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams for that for
показуе информация про стримы тому для
that, for that, Mali  operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
to be written directly at once
пишиться прямо зараз
Apik there in telegra okm vdeo more tezh
Апик там в телегра окм вдео ще теж
tsikava and korisna information and we are responsible
цикава и корисна информация и мы повинни
for you trima postiyny operational
з вами трима постийний оперативный
link
звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you about it
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine subscribe
YouTube Слава Украине подпишись